<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Money on Thejazeto Lhousa</title><link>/tags/money/</link><description>Recent content in Money on Thejazeto Lhousa</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>©thejazeto</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 05:27:54 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/money/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Favorite Finance Apps</title><link>/posts/favorite-finance-apps/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 05:27:54 +0530</pubDate><guid>/posts/favorite-finance-apps/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="bank-apps">Bank apps&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The banks own apps to manage accounts.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>For the purposes of checking statements. Basic banking.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="cred">CRED&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>For tracking my credit cards and their due dates so that I don&amp;rsquo;t miss anything.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It also gives a very nice visual of the statements for the billing cycles. The raw PDFs generated by banks are too unorganized and hard to read.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="indmoney">INDmoney&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Tracking all my assets and liabilities. All my investments, stocks, EPF, savings and insurances get tracked here.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It also helps manage your goals and gives a projection of whether and when it will be attained.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="paytm-money">Paytm Money&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>This is the main app I use to invest in mutual funds and gold.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="money-mgr">Money Mgr.&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>This app is for tracking all my daily expenses and income. I make entries whenever there is a transaction.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Helps give a bigger picture and spend habits over the weeks or months.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="kite">Kite&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>This is where I tried to invest in Indian stocks.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Not really keeping up though. Managing individual stocks needs dedication. Parking this for now.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="smallcase">Smallcase&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Just signed up. Seems like a pretty good app. This investment vehicle is like MFs but with more control over the individual equity.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>