<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Productivity on Thejazeto Lhousa</title><link>/tags/productivity/</link><description>Recent content in Productivity on Thejazeto Lhousa</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>©thejazeto</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 03:40:55 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/productivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My Dev Journal V3</title><link>/posts/my-dev-journal-v3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 03:40:55 +0530</pubDate><guid>/posts/my-dev-journal-v3/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Refer blogs for &lt;a href="https://www.thejazeto.com/posts/my-dev-journal/">v1&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://www.thejazeto.com/posts/my-dev-journal-v2/">v2&lt;/a> for more history about this&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>And here&amp;rsquo;s a reminder on how important it is to document: &lt;a href="https://jvns.ca/blog/brag-documents/">https://jvns.ca/blog/brag-documents/&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Dev journal v2 has done a pretty good job for me. I recently also added a functionality on my windows laptop to sync it up to a cloud storage (onedrive) via a windows automation scheduler called &amp;ldquo;Task Scheduler&amp;rdquo; at regular intervals of the day. I gotta say it&amp;rsquo;s pretty neat feature which I didn&amp;rsquo;t know about.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Dev Journal V2</title><link>/posts/my-dev-journal-v2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 01:35:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>/posts/my-dev-journal-v2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Since the first blog on a dev journal &lt;a href="https://www.thejazeto.com/posts/my-dev-journal/">here&lt;/a>, I&amp;rsquo;ve made some changes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With the onset of LLMs I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten help from chatGPT to upgrade my dev journal workflow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some things that have not changed are the log markdown file(daily_log.md) where your logs go into and the alias names.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Things that have changed:&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="1-shell-script">1) Shell script&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Instead of having a cron job update the daily dates and month headers on a set time, which can and will fail to run if your machine is not ON at the time of cron schedule. So instead this script below will be used to do regex checks on the log file and update dates and months as required.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Util: CLI Dictionary</title><link>/posts/util-cli-dict/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 22:05:07 +0530</pubDate><guid>/posts/util-cli-dict/</guid><description>&lt;p>I end up having to lookup certain words which I&amp;rsquo;m not familiar with often and even though spotlight(macOS) provides quick lookup sometimes it mixes up with other files or OS related applications.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So if you are someone who finds yourself in the terminal most of your days this will be helpful.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-youll-need">What you&amp;rsquo;ll need&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Terminal&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>curl&lt;/code> CLI tool (which is inbuilt in most cases)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>jq&lt;/code> CLI command (google &amp;ldquo;how to install jq in &lt;em>your_os&lt;/em>)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s it!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Dev Journal (could be yours too)</title><link>/posts/my-dev-journal/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 20:23:12 +0530</pubDate><guid>/posts/my-dev-journal/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you read tech blogs you’ll come across articles stating how important how important it is to maintain a dev journal or bragging doc or what have you. Basically it’s just a doc where you track all that you have done, read, watched, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Your brain being a finite resource can only hold so much information. Over time you lose track of the code change you made, the valuable life advice you gave to that junior, some quote someone said over a meeting. Okay that’s going overboard but you get the gist.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>